[
  {
    "id": "1312",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:1",
    "question": "When the Book of Jacob begins; how many years had passed away since Lehi and his party left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": ["55"],
    "options": ["25", "55", "75"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1313",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "How many chapters are there in the Book of Jacob?",
    "answer": ["7"],
    "options": ["5", "6", "7"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1314",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:1",
    "question": "Jacob was commanded by the Lord to write the words which he wrote in what is now known to us as- the Book of Jacob.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1315",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:1",
    "question": "On what size of plates did Jacob write the things which he was commanded by Nephi?",
    "answer": ["Small"],
    "options": ["Large", "Small", "Very Small"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1316",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:2",
    "question": "Jacob wrote upon the plates a _____ of the things which he considered to be most precious.",
    "answer": ["Few"],
    "options": ["A Lot", "Few", "Bunch"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1317",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:2",
    "question": "Jacob was not to touch, save it were lightly, concerning the history of the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1318",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "The history of Jacob’s people should be engraved on other plates.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1319",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "Jacob said that the history of his people would be engraved on more than one set of plates.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1320",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "Jacob was commanded by Nephi to preserve these plates and hand them down unto his seed, from generation to _____.",
    "answer": ["Generation"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1321",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:4",
    "question": "Jacob was to engrave the heads of them upon the plates, if they were preaching which was sacred, or revelation which was great, or prophesying.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1322",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:4",
    "question": "Jacob was to touch or write upon the plates as much as it was possible, for ____ sake, and for the sake of his people.",
    "answer": ["Christ’s"],
    "options": ["His", "Christ’s", "The Devils"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1323",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:5",
    "question": "Because of _____ and great anxiety, it truly had been made manifest unto Jacob’s people, what things should happen to them.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1324",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:6",
    "question": "Jacob and his people had many revelations, and the spirit of much _____.",
    "answer": ["Prophecy"],
    "options": ["Thinking", "Prophecy", "Foolishness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1325",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:6",
    "question": "Because of revelation and much prophecy, Jacob and his people knew of Jesus Christ; and his kingdom which should come.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1326",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac:17",
    "question": "Wherefore Jacob labored _____ among his people to persuade them to come to Christ and partake of his goodness.",
    "answer": ["Diligently"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1327",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:8",
    "question": "Jacob wanted to persuade all men not to rebel against God, and provoke him to get angry.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1328",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:8",
    "question": "God does not get angry with the children of men.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1329",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:9",
    "question": "Jacob hoped that all men would believe in Christ, and view his death, and suffer his cross and bear the shame of the world.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1330",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:9",
    "question": "Jacob took it upon himself to fulfill the _____ of his brother Nephi.",
    "answer": ["Commandment"],
    "options": ["Commandment", "Words", "Record"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1332",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:9",
    "question": "Nephi anointed a man to be a king and ruler of his people, according to the reigns of kings.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1333",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "The Nephites loved Nephi _____.",
    "answer": ["Exceedingly"],
    "options": ["Truly", "Exceedingly", "So And So"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1334",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "Nephi had been a great protector of the Nephites and had wielded the sword of _____ in their defense.",
    "answer": ["Laban"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1335",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "Nephi did not labor very much in his days with the Nephites for their welfare.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1336",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:11",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to honor and retain in remembrance his name, so whoever reigned in his stead was called 2nd Nephi, 3rd Nephi, and so forth.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1337",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:12",
    "question": "When Nephi died, the words that were spoken during his funeral are written down for us to read and remember.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1338",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:13",
    "question": "There were many people during Jacob’s day and that put the suffix-ites, according to the name of their Leaders.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1339",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:14",
    "question": "Jacob would not distinguish some of the different tribes or people by their names of their leaders.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1340",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that those that were friendly toward the Nephites’, or the people of Nephi were Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1341",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:14",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that those that seeked to destroy the Nephites were called Lamanites, according to the reigns of the kings.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1342",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "In what reign of king did the Nephites begin to grow hard in their hearts, and indulge themselves somewhat in wicked practices.",
    "answer": ["2nd"],
    "options": ["2nd", "3rd", "4th"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1343",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "Jacob compared the Nephites practices like of King David of old, desiring many wives and _____.",
    "answer": ["Concub1nes"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1344",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "Jacob mentioned what son of King David of the bible in his writings.",
    "answer": ["Solomon"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1345",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:16",
    "question": "The Nephites began to search for much gold, and silver, and be lifted up somewhat in their pride.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1346",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:17",
    "question": "Jacob taught the Nephites the words that were taught to him in the _____ by the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Temple"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1347",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:18, 2Nep5:6",
    "question": "Jacob and his younger brother _____ were consecrated priests and teachers by the hand of Nephi.",
    "answer": ["Joseph"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1348",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph did not magnify their offices or callings unto the Lord.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1349",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph took upon the responsibility, answering the sins of the people upon their heads if they did not teach them the word of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1350",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "If Jacob and Joseph did not labor diligently, the blood of the Nephites would come upon their garments on judgment day.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1351",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:19",
    "question": "It is safe to assume that Jacob and Joseph will be found spotless at the last day.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1352",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:2",
    "question": "Jacob did not magnify his office with soberness as he ought to have had: As to rid his garments of the Nephites sins.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1353",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:2",
    "question": "Jacob declared the word of God unto the Nephites in a _____.",
    "answer": ["Temple"],
    "options": ["Church", "Temple", "Salt Box"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1354",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:3",
    "question": "Jacob was weighed down with much desire and anxiety for the welfare of the Nephites _____.",
    "answer": ["Souls"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1355",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:5",
    "question": "Jacob did not refer to Jesus Christ as the Creator.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1356",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:5",
    "question": "The Nephites were beginning to labor in sin, which appeared very abominable unto him and unto God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1357",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:6",
    "question": "Because of the sins of the Nephites- it grieved Jacob’s soul, and caused him to shrink before his _____.",
    "answer": ["Maker"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1358",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:6",
    "question": "Jacob testified before his Maker, concerning the wickedness of the hearts of the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1359",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:7",
    "question": "It grieved Jacob that he had to use so much boldness of speech concerning the Nephites, before their _____ and their children.",
    "answer": ["Wives"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1360",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:7",
    "question": "The feelings of the Nephites wives and children were exceedingly tender and chaste and delicate before God, which thing is pleasing unto God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1361",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:8",
    "question": "The pleasing _____ or words of God could heal the wounded soul of the Nephites and can also be applied unto us.",
    "answer": ["Word"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1362",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:9",
    "question": "Jacob was given a _____ commandment by God to admonish the Nephites according to their crimes and to enlarge the wounds of those who they have already wounded.",
    "answer": ["Strict"],
    "options": ["Strict", "Lesser", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1363",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:9",
    "question": "Jacob was told to say other words by God, instead of consoling and healing those that had been wounded.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1364",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:9",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Nephites had placed _____ to pierce their souls and wound their delicate minds in those that they had already wounded.",
    "answer": ["Daggers"],
    "options": ["Knives", "Daggers", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1365",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:10",
    "question": "Jacob was to tell his people concerning their wickedness, and _____, in the presence of the pure in heart, and the broken heart.",
    "answer": ["Abominations"],
    "options": ["Looks", "Doings", "Abominations"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1366",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:10",
    "question": "According to Jacob, the Almighty God has a piercing eye and can see us in a glance.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1367",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:11",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites the truth according to the plainness of the word of _____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1368",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:11",
    "question": "Jacob would never inquire of the Lord, and instead, relied upon his own wisdom and understanding.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1369",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:11",
    "question": "Jacob was told by the Lord to go up into the _____, and declare the word which I will give thee unto this people.",
    "answer": ["Temple"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1370",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:12",
    "question": "Jacob said that the land of promise had _____, silver, and all manner of precious ores.",
    "answer": ["Gold"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1371",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac1:13",
    "question": "Some of the Nephites had obta1ned more abundantly than their brethren, and were lifted up in the pride of their hearts.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1372",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:13",
    "question": "Some of the Nephites would wear stiff necks and high heads because of the costl1ness of their _____.",
    "answer": ["Apparel"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1373",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:13",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that some of the Nephites would persecute their brethren because some had more worldly things than others.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1374",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:14",
    "question": "But he has condemned you, and if you persist in your evil ways his judgments must _____ come unto you.",
    "answer": ["Speedily"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1375",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:15",
    "question": "Jacob wished the Lord would show the Nephites that he could pierce them with the glance of his eye and smite them to the _____!",
    "answer": ["Dust"],
    "options": ["Sky", "Kingdom Come", "Dust"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1376",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:16",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his people to get rid of their iniquities and _____.",
    "answer": ["Abominations"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1377",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:16",
    "question": "O that you would listen unto the word of his commands and not let this _____ of your hearts destroy your souls!",
    "answer": ["Pride Or (b) Harlot"],
    "options": ["Lust", "Pride Or (b) Harlot"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1378",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:17",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his brethren to familiarize themselves to everyone else and to free themselves of their substance.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1379",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:18",
    "question": "But before ye seek for _____, seek ye; for the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": ["Riches-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1380",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:19",
    "question": "And after you have obta1ned a _____ in Christ you shall obtain riches.",
    "answer": ["Hope"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1381",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:19",
    "question": "After we obta1ned riches, we should clothe the naked, feed the hungry, and administer relief to the sick and the _____.",
    "answer": ["Afflicted"],
    "options": ["Poorest Of The Poor", "Afflicted", "Broken Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1382",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:21",
    "question": "The Lord esteems or thinks some people are better than others.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1383",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:21",
    "question": "The Lord told Jacob that all the flesh, are of the dust.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1384",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:21",
    "question": "The Lord did not create men to keep his commandments and glorify him forever.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1385",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:22",
    "question": "Jacob’s heart would rejoice exceedingly because of the things the Nephites were doing.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1386",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "The word of God burdens Jacob because he had to speak to the Nephites concerning their _____ crimes.",
    "answer": ["Grosser"],
    "options": ["Grosser", "Hateful", "War"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1387",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "The Nephites began to _____ in iniquity; and they did not understand the scriptures, and they seeked to excuse themselves of committing whoredoms.",
    "answer": ["Wax"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1388",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "Because of the things written about David, and Solomon his son, the Nephites did not understand the scriptures.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1389",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:24",
    "question": "Behold, David and Solomon truly had many wives and concub1nes, and it was an abominable thing before the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1390",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:25",
    "question": "The Lord did not lead the people out of Jerusalem, so that he could rise up a righteous branch out of the loins of Joseph.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1391",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:26",
    "question": "The Lord would not suffer that the Nephites would do the same things as those of ancient times.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1392",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:27",
    "question": "Jacob wanted the _____ to hearken unto the words of the Lord; and have one wife and no concub1nes.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1393",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:28",
    "question": "“For I, the Lord God, delight in the _____ of women”.",
    "answer": ["Chastity"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1394",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:28",
    "question": "Whoredoms are an; _____ before me; thus saith the Lord of Host.",
    "answer": ["Abomination"],
    "options": ["Ugly", "Atrocity", "Abomination"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1395",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:29",
    "question": "The Lord said that if the Nephites did not keep his commandments, he would curse the land for their sakes.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1396",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:31",
    "question": "The Lord did not see the sorrow, neither the mourning of the daughters of his people in the lands of Jerusalem and elsewhere.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1397",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:32",
    "question": "I will not suffer that the cries of the fair daughters of Jerusalem; shall come up unto me against the men of my people, saith the Lord of Hosts.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1398",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:33",
    "question": "The Lord said that the Nephites should lead away in captivity the daughters of his people because of their tenderness.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1399",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:34",
    "question": "And now behold, my brethren, ye know that these commandments were given to our father, _____.",
    "answer": ["Lehi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1400",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Nephites had done greater iniquities than their brethren, the _____.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1401",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "The Nephites had broken the heart of their tender wives, and lost the confidence of their _____.",
    "answer": ["Children"],
    "options": ["Lord", "Children", "Horses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1402",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Because of the bad example before their children, the soberness of their hearts ascended up to God against them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1403",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Jacob wrote:  Because of the strictness of the word of God, many hearts of women died, pierced with deep _____.",
    "answer": ["Wounds"],
    "options": ["Wounds", "Daggers", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1404",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac2:1-35",
    "question": "Jacob taught humility and morality in chapter two, in his writings or book.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1405",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob said that he would speak to those that are pure in _____.",
    "answer": ["Heart"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1406",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob said to look unto God with a firmness of _____, and pray unto him with exceeding faith.",
    "answer": ["Mind"],
    "options": ["Belief", "Mind", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1407",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites that if they would pray, God would plead their cause and send down justice upon those that seek to destroy them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1408",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:2",
    "question": "All you that are pure in heart; lift up your _____ and receive the pleasing word of God.",
    "answer": ["Heads"],
    "options": ["Heads", "Swords", "Arms"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1409",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:3",
    "question": "Jacob said: “Woe, Woe, Woe, unto those that are pure in heart; that are filthy this day before God”.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1410",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:3",
    "question": "What tribe of people, are cursed with a sore cursing and shall scourge the Nephites even unto destruction?",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1411",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:4",
    "question": "And the time speedily comes that the Lord will lead away the righteous from among the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1412",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "The Nephites hated the _____ because of their filth1ness and the cursing which had come upon their skin.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1413",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "At the time that Jacob wrote the words in chapter three of his book; the Lamanites were more righteous than the _____.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1414",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "The Lamanites were more righteous than the Nephites because they observed to keep the commandments of the Lord by having one wife and no concub1nes.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1415",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites or a seed of them will become a blessed people in the last days.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1416",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:7",
    "question": "Jacob wrote: Their husbands love their wives, and their wives love their husbands; and their husbands and their wives love their _____.",
    "answer": ["Children"],
    "options": ["Gold", "Platinum", "Children"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1417",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:7",
    "question": "The Lamanites unbelief and hatred towards the Nephites was because the iniquity of their fathers.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1418",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:7",
    "question": "Jacob asked the Nephites:  How much better are you than they, in the sight of your great Creator?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1419",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:8",
    "question": "Jacob feared that the skin of the Lamanites would be whiter than that of the Nephites, when they would be brought with them before the throne of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1420",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:8",
    "question": "Jacob did never, mentioned God having a throne of any kind.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1421",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:9",
    "question": "Jacob reminded the Nephites to look upon their own filth1ness and to remember that the filth1ness of the_____ came because or their fathers.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1422",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:10",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites to remember their children and how much grief they had brought upon them, because of their bad examples.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1423",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:10",
    "question": "It was the Nephites strength and power that would bring their children unto destruction.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1424",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "O my brethren, hearken unto my word; arouse the _____ of your soul; shake yourselves that ye may awake from the slumber of death.",
    "answer": ["Faculties"],
    "options": ["Faculties", "Body", "Frame"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1425",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "If we are to loose ourselves from the chains of hell, we will become angels of the devil.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1426",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "If we are cast into the lake of fire and brimstone, we will receive what is called a _____ death.",
    "answer": ["Second"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1427",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone is also called a second death by Jacob.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1428",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:12",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to the Nephites concerning _____ and lasciviousness, and every other kind of sin.",
    "answer": ["Fornication"],
    "options": ["Adultery", "Fornication", "Marriage"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1429",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:12",
    "question": "Jacob did not tell the Nephites concerning their sins and the awful consequences of them.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1430",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "A _____ part of the proceedings of the Nephites cannot be written upon the plates that Jacob was talking about.",
    "answer": ["Hundredth"],
    "options": ["Thousand", "Hundredth", "Million"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1431",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "Many of the proceedings of the Nephites are written on much smaller plates.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1432",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "The large plates of the Nephites contain their wars, and contentions, and the _____ of their kings.",
    "answer": ["Reigns"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1433",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "The plates that contain the words of Jacob; are called the plates of Jacob.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1434",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "By whose hand were the plates of Jacob made?",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1435",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "Jacob could not make his own plates because he _____.",
    "answer": ["We Don’t Know Why"],
    "options": ["Had Arthritis", "Did Not Know How", "We Don’t Know Why"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1436",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:1",
    "question": "Jacob did not minister the words of Christ unto his people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1437",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:1",
    "question": "Jacob could not write but a little of his words upon the plates because of the difficulty in engraving.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1438",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:1",
    "question": "Jacob knew nevertheless, that the things which he and Nephi wrote upon the plates would one day be erased or destroyed.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1439",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:2",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that he and Nephi could write on other things besides the plates and they would not perish or vanish.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1440",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:2",
    "question": "Because the Lord would protect their writings; Jacob knew that they could write upon plates of Brass.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1441",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:2",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wrote in order to give their children, and beloved brethren, a small degree of knowledge concerning them and their fathers.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1442",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:3",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob labored diligently to engrave words on the plates in order that their children and their brethren, world receive them with thankful _____.",
    "answer": ["Hearts"],
    "options": ["Souls", "Hearts", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1443",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:3",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wanted their brethren to look upon the plates and learn with joy and not sorrow, neither with contempt, concerning their last parents.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1444",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob wrote with the intent that their brethren would know that they knew of _____.",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1445",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob knew of Jesus Christ and had a hope of his glory a _____ years before his coming.",
    "answer": ["100"],
    "options": ["1,000", "200", "100"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1446",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "The holy prophets also had a hope of Jesus Christ and his glory, even those that came before Nephi and Jacob and testified before his actual coming.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1447",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "The holy prophets believed in Christ and worshiped the _____ in his name, and also Jacob and Nephi worshiped the Father in his name.",
    "answer": ["Father"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1448",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "The intent that Jacob and his people kept the Law of Moses; was that it would point their souls to the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1449",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "Jacob only mentioned Abraham the father of Isaac, once in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1450",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "When Abraham offered Isaac unto God, it was a similitude of God and his Only_____ Son.",
    "answer": ["Begotten"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1451",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:6",
    "question": "We search the prophets, and have the many revelations and the spirit of prophecy; we obtain a hope and our faith becomes unshaken.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1452",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:6",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wrote that they can command in the name of _____; and the very trees obey us, or the mountains, or the waves of the sea.",
    "answer": ["Jesus"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1453",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:7",
    "question": "Jacob wrote: nevertheless, the Lord God shows us our weakness that we may know that it is by his grace and his great condescensions, that they have power to do these things.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1454",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Lord’s works were no big deal and not very marvelous.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1455",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that it is impossible for man to know all the mysterious and the ways of our Heavenly Father.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1456",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "And no man knows the ways of the Lord, except it be revealed unto him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1457",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:8",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren not to despise the _____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Revelations"],
    "options": ["Things", "Revelations", "Glory"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1458",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:9",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that by the power of God’s word, man came upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1459",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:10",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren to seek not to _____ the Lord, but to take counsel from his hand.",
    "answer": ["Counsel"],
    "options": ["Question", "Criticize", "Counsel"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1460",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:10",
    "question": "God counsels in _____, and in justice, and in great mercy, over all his works.",
    "answer": ["Wisdom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1461",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:11",
    "question": "Jacob told us to be _____ unto God through the atonement of Christ, his Only Begotten Son, and ye may obtain a resurrection.",
    "answer": ["Reconciled"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1462",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:12",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren to marvel at the things that he had spoken to them, and not to publicly speak of the atonement of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1463",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "According to Jacob, the Spirit speaks the truth and lies when it only benefits us.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1464",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "Wherefore, the Spirit speaks of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be, wherefore, these things are manifested plainly unto us.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1465",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "Jacob said that we ourselves, are the only witnesses to and of the things the Spirit tells us.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1466",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "God is also a witness to the things the Spirit witnesses to us and also are his _____.",
    "answer": ["Prophets"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1467",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "But behold, the _____ were a stiffnecked people, and they despised the words of plainness.",
    "answer": ["Jews"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1468",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Who killed the prophets, and sought for things they could not understand?",
    "answer": ["Jews"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1469",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Wherefore because of their blindness, which blindness came by looking beyond the _____.",
    "answer": ["Mark"],
    "options": ["Truth", "Mark", "Point"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1470",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "The Jews must fall, because they were looking beyond the mark.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1471",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Why did God take away his plainness from the Jews, and delivered unto them many things which they could not understand?",
    "answer": ["They Desired It"],
    "options": ["They Deserved It", "They Desired It", "We Don’t Know"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1472",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "The Jews stumbled because of the things they desired and the Lord has done it.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1473",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:15",
    "question": "Who led Jacob to prophesy of things to his brothers?",
    "answer": ["The Spirit"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "The Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1474",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:15",
    "question": "Jacob prophesied that by the stumbling of the _____ they will reject the very stone upon which they might build and have a safe foundation.",
    "answer": ["Jews"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1475",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac4:16",
    "question": "According to the _____ this stone shall become the great, and the last, and the only foundation, upon which the Jews can build.",
    "answer": ["Scriptures"],
    "options": ["Scriptures", "Prophets", "The Koran"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1476",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac4:17 & Jac5:50-77",
    "question": "Jacob said that it is possible for the Jews to build a foundation on the stone even after they have rejected it.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1477",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:1",
    "question": "What prophet of old did Jacob refer to in Chapter 5 concerning the allegory of the tame and wild olive tree?",
    "answer": ["Zenos"],
    "options": ["Zenock", "Zenos", "Zeniff"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1479",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:19",
    "question": "In what part of the v1neyard did the Lord and the servant look to see if the natural branches of the tree which they had planted had brought forth much fruit.",
    "answer": ["Nethermost"],
    "options": ["Southernmost", "Nethermost", "Northernmost"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1480",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:2",
    "question": "The nethermost part of the v1neyard was the poorest spot in all the land of the v1neyard.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1481",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:21",
    "question": "The Lord told the servant not to question him or counsel him on the spot that he had chosen for the tree.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1482",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:22",
    "question": "The Lord did not know that it was the poorest place in the v1neyard to plant the olive tree.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1483",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:22",
    "question": "Because the Lord had nourished the tree for a long time, it had brought much fruit.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1484",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:49",
    "question": "The Lord asked the servant what he could have done more for his v1neyard.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1485",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:50",
    "question": "The servant told the Lord of the v1neyard to do what to the tree to bring more good fruit.",
    "answer": ["Spare It A Little Longer"],
    "options": [
      "Cut It And Start Again",
      "Spare It A Little Longer",
      "To Forget About It Because It Was Useless"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1486",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:59",
    "question": "Why did the Lord of the v1neyard pluck the ripened branches from the tree?",
    "answer": ["Hoped The Roots May Take Strength Because Of Their Goodness"],
    "options": [
      "Because They Smelled Bad",
      "Hoped The Roots May Take Strength Because Of Their Goodness",
      "We Don’t Know"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1487",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:59",
    "question": "Because of the changes the Lord of the v1neyard had done to the branches of the olive tree; he hoped that good may overcome the evil.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1488",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:61",
    "question": "The Lord of the v1neyard told his servant go to, and call servants, that we may labor _____ with our might in the v1neyard.",
    "answer": ["Diligently"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1489",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:71",
    "question": "If we labor with our might in the v1neyard of the Lord, he has said that we shall have joy in the fruit which he shall lay up unto himself.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1490",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:74",
    "question": "The natural fruit of the v1neyard of the Lord is the most _____ unto him from the beginning.",
    "answer": ["Precious"],
    "options": ["Desirable", "Precious", "Most Worthy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1491",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:75",
    "question": "Who was the Lord of the v1neyard referring to when he said “Blessed art thou; for because you have been diligent in laboring with me in the v1neyard”?",
    "answer": ["Servants"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1492",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "There will come a time when the evil fruit shall come again into the v1neyard of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1493",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "In the end; the Lord of the v1neyard will cause that both the good and the _____ fruit shall be gathered; and the good will he preserve unto himself.",
    "answer": ["Bad-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1494",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "What will happen to the Lord’s v1neyard in the end?",
    "answer": ["Be Burned With Fire"],
    "options": [
      "Be Burned With Fire",
      "Will Become Flooded",
      "Be Bombed By Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1495",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:1",
    "question": "In the allegory of the olive-tree, what prophet spoke concerning the house of Israel in which he likened them unto a tame olive-tree that must surely come to pass?",
    "answer": ["Zenos"],
    "options": ["Zenock", "Zenos", "Zeniff"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1496",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:2",
    "question": "In the last time-Who shall go forth in his power to nourish and prune his v1neyard?",
    "answer": ["His Servants"],
    "options": ["Muslims", "His Servants", "Migrant Workers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1497",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:2",
    "question": "After his servants prune his v1neyard; the end soon comes.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1498",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:3",
    "question": "Those that have labored diligently in his v1neyard will not be blessed?",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1499",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:3",
    "question": "_____ are they who shall be cast out into their own place!",
    "answer": ["Cursed"],
    "options": ["Damned", "Perish", "Cursed"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1500",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:2-3",
    "question": "The world in the last day will be burned by fire.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1501",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "And how _____ is our God unto us, for he has remembered the house of Israel.",
    "answer": ["Merciful"],
    "options": ["Merciful", "Thoughtful", "Diligent"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1502",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "The Lord our God has also remembered both _____ and branches of the house of Israel.",
    "answer": ["Roots"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1503",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "God _____ forth his hand unto all his people all day long.",
    "answer": ["Stretches"],
    "options": ["Extends", "Stretches", "Gives"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1504",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say were gainsaying and stiffnecked people?",
    "answer": ["A And B"],
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Those Of The House Of Israel", "A And B"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1505",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "Those that harden their hearts shall be saved in the kingdom of God?",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1506",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "Jacob beseech to us in words of soberness that we would _____.",
    "answer": ["Repent"],
    "options": ["Believe His Words", "Repent", "Not Go To Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1507",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "Jacob wants us to come with a full purpose of heart and cleave unto God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1508",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "Jacob said that God “cleaves” unto us.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1509",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "We should cleave unto our______ while we are in this mortal life",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["God", "Our Riches", "Our Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1510",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:5",
    "question": "We should not harden our hearts when the arm of mercy from the Lord is extended to us.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1511",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:7",
    "question": "Jacob said, “For behold, after you have been _____ by the good word of God all day long”.",
    "answer": ["Nourished"],
    "options": ["Bless", "Nourished", "Astonished"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1512",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:7",
    "question": "If we bring forth evil fruit, we must be hewn down and cast into the fire.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1513",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:9",
    "question": "Jacob said the Nephites did not know that the power of the redemption and the resurrection, which is in Christ.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1514",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:9",
    "question": "According to the power of Justice, the power of the redemption and resurrection which is in Christ can be denied.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1515",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:10",
    "question": "Who or what has flames that are unquenchable?",
    "answer": ["The Lake Of Fire And Brimstone"],
    "options": ["The Lake Of Fire And Brimstone", "An Atomic Blast", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1516",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac6:10",
    "question": "What did Jacob say is another name for endless torment?",
    "answer": ["brimstone"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1517",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:11",
    "question": "What gate did Jacob want us to enter?",
    "answer": ["The Strait And Narrow"],
    "options": [
      "Pearly Gates",
      "The Strait And Narrow",
      "The Long And Winding Gate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1518",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:11",
    "question": "Jacob wanted us to enter the strait and narrow gate until we shall obtain eternal life.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1519",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:12",
    "question": "In Jacob chapter six; Jacob said- “O be wise; what can I say more”.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1520",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac6:13",
    "question": "Jacob bid us farewell until we shall meet him before the pleasing bar of God.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1521",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac6:13",
    "question": "What thing or bar “strikes the wicked with awful dread and fear”.",
    "answer": ["Pleasing Bar Of God"],
    "options": ["#10 Rebar", "Snickers Bar", "Pleasing Bar Of God"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1522",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:1",
    "question": "Who is considered, by many Book of Mormon scholars; to be the first anti-Christ mentioned in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Sharem"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1523",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:1",
    "question": "In the beginning of chapter 7 what did Sharem do or say to the people of Nephi?",
    "answer": ["There Should Be No Christ"],
    "options": [
      "Christ Had Already Came",
      "There Should Be No Christ",
      "Jesus Is Not The Messiah"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1524",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:2",
    "question": "Sharem did not flatter many Nephites with his flattering words.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1525",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:2",
    "question": "Sharem was trying to do what with his flattering words?",
    "answer": ["Overthrow The Doctr1ne Of Christ"],
    "options": [
      "Say That God Loves All People",
      "Say That He Was The Messiah",
      "Overthrow The Doctr1ne Of Christ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1526",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Sharem labor diligently that he might lead away the hearts of the people.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1527",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Even though Shem used many flattering words; he did not lead away or astray many of the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1528",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Sharem did not know that Jacob had faith in Christ.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1529",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "In chapter #7; who did Jacob have faith in?",
    "answer": ["In Christ"],
    "options": ["His Own Wisdom", "In Christ", "The Words Of Plato"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1530",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:3",
    "question": "Who sought much opportunity that he might come unto Jacob?",
    "answer": ["Sharem"],
    "options": ["Moroni", "Lehi", "Sharem"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1531",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Sharem was not very wise or learned individual?",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1532",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Sharem had a_____ knowledge of the language of the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["Perfect"],
    "options": ["So And So", "Perfect", "Better"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1533",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Because of Sharem’s knowledge of the language of the Nephites he used much _____.",
    "answer": ["Flattery"],
    "options": ["Flattery", "Wisdom", "Understanding"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1534",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Sharem had much power in his oratory or speech.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1535",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:4",
    "question": "Who gave Sharem the power of his speech?",
    "answer": ["The Devil Or Satan"],
    "options": ["Jesus Christ", "God", "The Devil Or Satan"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1536",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Sharem had hoped to shake Jacob of his _____.",
    "answer": ["Faith"],
    "options": ["Status", "Faith", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1537",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Jacob had seen many revelations concerning the doctr1ne of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1538",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "What had Jacob seen that ministered unto him?",
    "answer": ["Angels"],
    "options": ["Demons", "Angels", "UFO’s"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1539",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Whose voice had Jacob heard from time to time?",
    "answer": ["The Lord’s"],
    "options": ["His Own", "The Lord’s", "Satan’s"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1540",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:5",
    "question": "Because of the voice Jacob had heard; he could not be shaken from his faith, by the evil Sharem.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1541",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:6",
    "question": "When Sharem first saw Jacob; he called him",
    "answer": ["Brother Jacob"],
    "options": ["Hey Dude", "Brother Jacob", "Jacob"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1542",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:6",
    "question": "Sharem had not sought much opportunity to speak with Jacob.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1543",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:6",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of preaching the gospel or the doctr1ne of Christ?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1544",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of leading away many of the Nephites unto perverting the right way of _____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["Satan", "God", "The World"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1545",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "What law did Sharem say was the “right way”?",
    "answer": ["Law Of Moses"],
    "options": ["Law Of Physics", "Law Of Moses", "The Articles Of Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1546",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Sharem said that Moses or the “Law of Moses” had already come to pass.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1547",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Sharem tries to confuse Jacob or us by first saying that the Law of Moses is the right way, then saying that no man knows of the things to come.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1548",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "In chapter #7, Sharem accuses Jacob of being a_____.",
    "answer": ["Blasphemy"],
    "options": ["False Prophet", "Blasphemy", "We Don’t Know What"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1549",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:7",
    "question": "Jacob did not write unto us the matter of which Sharem contended with him.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1550",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:8",
    "question": "The Lord God poured his _____ into Jacob’s soul.",
    "answer": ["Spirit"],
    "options": ["Thoughts", "Words", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1551",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:8",
    "question": "Because the Lord had poured his Spirit unto Jacob; he confounded Sharem in all his words.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1552",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "Jacob said to Sharem: “Denies thou the _____ who should come'?",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["3 Days Of Darkness", "Hailey’s Comet", "Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1553",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "Sharem said that if there would be a Christ, he would deny him or his existence.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1554",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob who said: “There is no Christ, neither has been, nor ever will be”?",
    "answer": ["Sharem"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1555",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:10",
    "question": "Sharem told Jacob the he believed the scriptures.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1556",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:10",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob; what did Jacob ask Sharem if he believed in what?",
    "answer": ["The Scriptures"],
    "options": [
      "Einstein’s Theory Of Relativity",
      "The Scriptures",
      "The Book Of Mormon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1557",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Jacob said that Sharem did not understand the scriptures.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1558",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say the scriptures testify of?",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1559",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say had written and testified concerning Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": ["The Prophets"],
    "options": ["Satan", "The Mormon’s", "The Prophets"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1560",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "Jacob had seen and heard the things concerning Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1561",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "By who or what power did the things concerning Jesus Christ been manifested to Jacob?",
    "answer": ["The Holy Ghost"],
    "options": ["Jesus Christ", "God", "The Holy Ghost"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1562",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "Jacob said that if there should be no _____ made, all mankind would be lost.",
    "answer": ["Atonement"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1563",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:13",
    "question": "Sharem asked Jacob to show him a sign of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1564",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:13",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of knowing much about this personage?",
    "answer": ["Ghost-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1565",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that he would not tempt God because Sharem knew that God did really exist.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1566",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob knew that if he would show Sherem a sign that Jesus Christ did really exist, he would still deny it.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1567",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob; Who said the words? “Art of the Devil”?",
    "answer": ["Jacob"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1568",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said told Sharem that thy will would be done.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1569",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "If God would smite Sharem, it would be a sign that he has great power?",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1570",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that God has great power both in _____ and in earth.",
    "answer": ["Heaven"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1571",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that Christ shall come, and that his will would be done.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1572",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Because Jacob spoke of many things concerning Jesus Christ; the power of the Lord came upon whom?",
    "answer": ["Jacob"],
    "options": ["Jacob", "Sharem", "The Devil"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1573",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob who fell to the earth because of the Lord’s great power?",
    "answer": ["Sharem"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1574",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob who was nourished of the power of Jesus Christ for many days.",
    "answer": ["Sharem"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1575",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "Sharem was nourished of the power of Jesus Christ for ____.",
    "answer": ["Many Days"],
    "options": ["Two Days", "Many Days", "Three Days"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1576",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:16",
    "question": "Who told the people to gather together because he wanted to speak to them before he died?",
    "answer": ["Sharem"],
    "options": ["Jacob", "Ishmael", "Sharem"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1577",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:16",
    "question": "Sharem the Anti-Christ knew the exact day that he would die.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1578",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Because Sharem did not speak very plainly to the Nephites, they could not understand him very well.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1579",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "In the end, Sharem denied the things that he had taught the _____.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1580",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Finally, in his last days, Sharem confessed of the existence of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1581",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Sharem confessed of the _____ of the Holy Ghost in the end.",
    "answer": ["Power"],
    "options": ["Reality", "Power", "Existence"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1582",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:17",
    "question": "Sharem did not believe in the ministering of angels.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1583",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:18",
    "question": "Sharem was deceived by the power of whom?",
    "answer": ["Satan-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1584",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:18",
    "question": "Sharem spoke of _____, and of eternity, and of eternal punishment.",
    "answer": ["Hell"],
    "options": ["Hell", "Nephi", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1585",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:19",
    "question": "Sharem felt that he had committed an unpardonable sin.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1586",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:19",
    "question": "Sharem said that he had lied unto God; and denied the Christ.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1587",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:20",
    "question": "When Sharem confessed of his wrongdoing he gave up the _____.",
    "answer": ["Ghost"],
    "options": ["Plates", "Ghost", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1588",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:21",
    "question": "The multitude had witnessed the things which Sharem had spoken at the end of his life.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1589",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "Jacob was not pleased when the power of God came onto the multitude after Sharem had spoken.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1591",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "Jacob had requested of _____ to show his matchless power to the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1592",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "At the end of chapter #7 of the Book of Jacob; God had heard whose cry and answered his prayer.",
    "answer": ["Jacob"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1593",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:23",
    "question": "What two things came to pass that was restored again among the people.",
    "answer": ["Peace And Love God"],
    "options": [
      "Freedom Of Speech And Writing",
      "Peace And Love God",
      "The Will Of Agency And Baptism"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "1594",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:23",
    "question": "The Nephites searched the_____, and hearkened, no more to the wicked man known as Sharem.",
    "answer": ["Scriptures"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1595",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob we are told that many ways were devised to reclaim and restore the Lamanites to the truth of the Gospel.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1596",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "The Lamanites delighted in wars and _____.",
    "answer": ["Bloodshed"],
    "options": ["Partying", "Whoredoms", "Bloodshed"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1597",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "The Lamanites had an_____ hatred for their brethren, the Nephites.",
    "answer": ["Eternal-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1598",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "Who sought by the power of their arms to destroy the Nephites?",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1599",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "The people of_____ fortified their armies against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Zoram", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1600",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "What people used their might, trusting in the God and the rock of their salvation?",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1601",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "Because the Nephites trusted in God; they became conquerors of their enemies, during Jacob’s life.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1602",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "When Jacob began to be old, he said that the record of the Nephites was kept on the other plates of _____.",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["Laban", "Nephi", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1603",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "Jacob concluded with his record, declaring that he had written according to the best of his_____.",
    "answer": ["Knowledge"],
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Penmanship", "Memory"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1604",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "Jacob said that his life and the lives of the Nephites had passed away like as it were a dream.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1605",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "In the end of his writings: What tribe of people did Jacob declare were wanderers?",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1606",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "The people of Nephi were lonesome and solemn people, cast out from what city.",
    "answer": ["Jerusalem"],
    "options": ["Salt Lake", "Dallas", "Jerusalem"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1607",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that he and his people were born in tribulation, and in a wilderness.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1608",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "What thing or attitude caused wars and contentions between the Nephites and Lamanites?",
    "answer": ["Hatred"],
    "options": ["Pride", "Hatred", "Agency"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1609",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:26",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob, he said that he and the people of Nephi mourn out our last days.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1610",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "At the end of his life, what son of Jacob took over the plates?",
    "answer": ["Enos"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1611",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Jacob was_____ when he passed away.",
    "answer": ["We Don’t Know"],
    "options": ["75", "100", "We Don’t Know"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1612",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "What is the name of Enos’s uncle who told Jacob of things he had commanded him to do?",
    "answer": ["Nephi"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1613",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Enos promised Jacob that he would be obedient unto his commands.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1614",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Jacob considered that his writing on the plates had been_____.",
    "answer": ["Small"],
    "options": ["Small", "Sufficient", "Too Much"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1615",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "At the end of his writing, Jacob bid us all farewell.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1616",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "Jacob hoped that of his many of his brethren would read his writings.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1617",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "What is the last word that is written in the Book of Jacob?",
    "answer": ["Adieu"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  }
]
